Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up a function to help us to check if we
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们成功地建立了一个函数来帮助我们检查我们是否
can start climbing. If the condition returns true, then we should enter the climb state
能否开始爬升。如果条件返回为真，那么我们应该进入攀爬状态
and if the condition is false. For example, when we are near a surface like this, we cannot
而如果条件为假。例如，当我们在像这样的表面附近时，我们不能
start climbing. And in this lecture, let's look at what entering climb state actually
开始攀爬。在本讲座中，让我们来看看进入爬升状态到底是什么意思
means. So inside of this character climb state, there are actually many things that we need
意义。所以在这个字符爬升状态中，实际上有许多事情我们需要
to handle. So first, we'll need to set our movement state. If you recall, in previous
来处理的。所以首先，我们需要设置我们的运动状态。如果你还记得，在以前的
lectures, we created a function called is climbing and that function is directly checking
讲座中，我们创建了一个叫做 "正在爬升 "的函数，该函数直接检查
if we are inside of the climb state. So that's the first thing that we need to do. After
该函数直接检查我们是否处于爬升状态。所以这是我们需要做的第一件事。在
checking, we should change our movement state to climb state. And after that, the first
检查之后，我们应该把我们的运动状态改为爬升状态。在这之后，第一件
thing that we need to handle is we need to handle the character's rotation and its capsule
我们需要处理的第一件事是我们需要处理角色的旋转和胶囊的高度。
height. So here I am inside of the character.cpp and you can see inside of the constructor,
高度。所以在这里我在character.cpp里面，你可以看到构造函数里面、
the first line here, it directly sets the capsule size. So the first value here, this
这里的第一行，它直接设置了胶囊的大小。所以这里的第一个值，这是
is the capsule radius and the second value, this is the capsule half height. When we start
是胶囊的半径，第二个值是胶囊的一半高度。当我们开始
climbing, because of the animation that we're going to use later, we'll need to decrease
攀爬时，由于我们稍后要使用的动画，我们将需要降低
the capsule height in order for it to fit with the animation. So that's the first thing that
为了与动画相适应，我们需要降低胶囊的高度。所以这就是我们需要处理的第一件事
we need to handle. And if you scroll down, you can see in here, it gets the character
我们需要处理。如果你往下看，你可以看到在这里，它得到了角色的运动组件，然后设置了这个面向B的组件。
movement component, then set this B-oriented rotation to movement to be true. So what this
运动组件，然后将这个面向B的旋转运动设置为真。所以这
does is this could allow character moves in the direction of input. When we start climbing,
是允许角色在输入方向上移动。当我们开始爬升时、
we want to disable this. After setting the rotation and the capsule height, the next
我们要禁用这个。在设置了旋转和胶囊高度之后，下一步是
thing, which is the key part, we need to handle the climb physics and its movement. So once
是关键的部分，我们需要处理攀爬物理学和它的运动。所以一旦
we are inside of our custom movement state, we'll need to handle all the movement physics
在我们的自定义运动状态中，我们将需要处理所有的运动物理学
inside of it in order to successfully move our character. So these are the physics functions
以便成功地移动我们的角色。所以这些是物理学函数
that handle the movement physics inside the character movement component. You can see
来处理角色运动组件中的运动物理学。你可以看到
for the walking mode, we have a physics walking function, we have a physics flying function
对于行走模式，我们有一个物理学行走函数，我们有一个物理学飞行函数
and a physics swimming function. After we set the movement to be custom, we'll need to
和一个物理游泳功能。在我们将运动设置为自定义后，我们将需要
manually override this function and fill in all the climb physics inside of it. We'll
手动覆盖这个函数，并在其中填入所有的攀爬物理学。我们将
look at how we can do that later. Once we successfully implemented climb physics, and
我们将在后面看一下我们如何做到这一点。一旦我们成功实现了爬升物理学，并且
the last thing that we need to handle is we need to handle exit climb state. So during
我们需要处理的最后一件事是我们需要处理退出爬升状态。所以在
climbing, there will be many cases that we should stop climbing. For instance, when the
攀爬过程中，会有很多情况下我们应该停止攀爬。例如，当
character has reached the ledge or the floor, or the player wants to leave the climb state
角色已经到达壁架或地板，或者玩家想通过输入离开攀爬状态
through input, we'll need to handle all of those cases as well. So in this lecture, we're
的时候，我们也需要处理所有这些情况。所以在本讲座中，我们将
going to take care of the first two steps. Go back to my project, I'm going to close
将处理前两个步骤。回到我的项目，我将关闭
my project. Then I'm going to go to the header file of my custom movement component, and I'm
我的项目。然后我将进入我的自定义运动组件的头文件，然后我将
going to scroll down. Inside of this climb core, I'm going to create a function. It's
向下滚动。在这个攀登核心里面，我将创建一个函数。它是
going to be void. I'm going to call this one start climbing. And we have start climbing,
将是无效的。我将把这个函数称为 "开始攀登"。我们有开始攀登、
we should have stop climbing. So I'm going to create another function for it. And it's
我们应该有停止攀登。所以我将为它创建另一个函数。它是
going to be stop climbing. All right, I'm going to create two function definitions and
将会是停止攀登。好的，我将创建两个函数定义，并且
I'm going to place this function under can start climbing. So place it in here, and I'm
我将把这个函数放在 "开始攀登 "下面。所以把它放在这里，而我将
going to place this stop climbing in here. So what I want to do inside of this start
把这个停止攀登放在这里。因此，我想在这个开始爬升中做什么？
climbing, I want to set the movement mode directly in here. So I'm going to set this
攀爬，我想直接在这里设置运动模式。所以我将设置这个
movement mode to move custom. Then for this new custom mode, this will be the enum that
运动模式移动自定义。然后对于这个新的自定义模式，这将是我们创建的枚举。
we created. So it will be E custom movement mode and double column, I'm going to fill
我们创建的枚举。所以它将是E自定义运动模式和双栏，我将填写
in this move climb. And for the stop climbing in here, I'm going to change the movement
在这个移动爬升中。对于这里的停止爬升，我将再次改变移动模式。
mode again, but this time I'm going to set the movement mode to move falling. So this
模式，但这次我要把运动模式设置为移动下降。所以这
should take care of exiting climb state. All right, I'm going to copy this function and
应该能处理好退出爬升状态的问题。好的，我将复制这个函数并
I'm going to paste it in here. So if can start climbing is true, I'm going to call the function
我要把它粘贴到这里。所以，如果可以开始爬升是真的，我将调用这个函数
start climbing. And if this be enabled climb is false, I'm going to call the function stop
start climbing。如果启用爬升是假的，我将调用函数停止
climbing. So this takes care of set movement state. And next one, we need to handle the
攀登。所以这就解决了设置运动状态的问题。接下来，我们需要处理
rotation during climbing and the capsule height. And to do that, there's one handy function
在爬升过程中的旋转和胶囊的高度。要做到这一点，有一个方便的函数
from parent class that we can use. So I'm going to go to my header file and I'm going
我们可以使用来自父类的一个方便的函数。所以我将进入我的头文件，然后我将
to go to this U character movement component. Inside of it, press control plus F to search.
转到这个U字符运动组件。在它里面，按control加F来搜索。
And the function that I'm searching for is called own movement mode change. So you can
我正在搜索的函数被称为自己的运动模式变化。所以你可以
see this is the function that we can override and this function here will be called after
你可以看到这是我们可以覆盖的函数，这个函数将在运动模式改变后被调用。
the movement mode has changed. So I'm going to directly override this function. So copy
运动模式改变后调用。所以我将直接覆盖这个函数。所以，复制
this and go back to my header file. I'm going to change this public section to protected
并回到我的头文件中。我将把这个公共部分改为受保护的
section and I'm going to paste the function in here and mark it as override. Then I'm
部分，然后把这个函数粘贴到这里，并把它标记为重写。然后我
going to create a function definition and I'm going to place the function under this
我将创建一个函数定义，并将该函数放在这个
tick component. I'm going to hide this climb traces region. So right after we changed the
滴答组件下。我将隐藏这个攀登痕迹区域。所以在我们改变了
movement mode, I'm going to check if is climbing is true. So that means we are inside of the
运动模式后，我将检查爬升是否为真。所以这意味着我们处于
climb state. And if that's the case, I'm going to set the Orion rotation to movement to be
爬升状态。如果是这样的话，我将把猎户座的旋转运动设置为
false. And I'm going to use the character owner to set the capsule half height. So I'm going
假的。我将使用字符所有者来设置胶囊的一半高度。所以我将
to use the function get capsule component. And in here we need to include the header
使用函数get capsule component。在这里，我们需要包括这个胶囊组件的头文件
file for this capsule component. So I'm going to directly search for it in here and type
文件。所以我将直接在这里搜索它，然后输入
in capsule component. And you can see this is the header file that we need to include.
capsule component。你可以看到这就是我们需要包含的头文件。
I'm going to go to the CPP file and I'm going to copy the first line and I'm going to paste
我将进入CPP文件，复制第一行并将其粘贴到
it in here. So I'm going to use the function inside of it. It's called set capsule half
它在这里。所以我将使用里面的函数。它的名字是set capsule half
height and the value here that I'm going to use. So it's going to be the half of the original
高度，我将在这里使用这个值。所以它将是原来的一半的
capsule half height. I'm going to go back to the character dot CPP and you can see the
胶囊的一半高度。我将回到字符点CPP，你可以看到
original half height is 96. F. So the half of it would be 48. F. So this takes care of
原来的半高是96。所以它的一半将是48。所以这就解决了
the rotation settings and the capsule half height when we're climbing and we also need
旋转设置和胶囊的半高，当我们爬升时，我们还需要
to reset them back after we exit the climb mode. We can do that through these two function
我们还需要在退出爬升模式后将它们重新设置回来。我们可以通过这两个函数
inputs. So you can see they're called previous movement mode and previous custom mode. So
输入。所以你可以看到它们被称为前一个运动模式和前一个自定义模式。所以
I'm going to do another if check in here. So if this previous movement mode is equal
我将在这里做另一个if检查。所以如果之前的运动模式等于
to move underscore custom and this previous custom mode is equal to the custom mode that
等于移动下划线自定义模式，并且这个先前的自定义模式等于我们创建的自定义模式。
we created. So it'll be E custom movement mode move climb. If this is true, then that
我们创建的自定义模式。所以它将是E自定义运动模式移动爬升。如果这是真的，那么这
means we have just exited the climb mode. In that case, I'm going to set this variable
意味着我们刚刚退出了爬升模式。在这种情况下，我将设置这个变量
back to true and I'm going to reset this capsule half height back to 96. F. Then I'm going
为真，并将这个胶囊的半身高度重置为96。F. 然后我将
to call the function stop movement immediately. So this should help us to clear any velocity
调用函数立即停止运动。所以这应该能帮助我们清除任何速度
that's from this climb mode. All right, one last thing. Since this is a virtual function
攀升模式的速度。好了，最后一件事。由于这是一个虚拟函数
and we are overriding it, don't forget to call super at the end. So I'm going to call
而且我们正在覆盖它，不要忘记在最后调用超级函数。所以我将会调用
super on movement mode changed and copy this function, copy this function inputs as well
超级运动模式改变，并复制这个函数，也复制这个函数输入
and paste them in here. Delete these two types. And that's pretty much it. I'm going to try
并把它们粘贴在这里。删除这两种类型。而这就差不多了。我将会尝试
to compile to see if there are any errors. I have a successful compile. I'm going to
编译，看看是否有任何错误。我有一个成功的编译。我将会
launch my editor back. You know, this is to find out if this is actually working. I'm
启动我的编辑器。你知道，这是为了找出这是否真的在工作。我将
going to go inside of this climb system folder and double click to open this BP climb system
我将进入这个攀登系统文件夹，双击打开这个BP攀登系统的
character. So I'm going to select this capsule component and in here for this hidden in game,
角色。所以我将选择这个胶囊组件，并在这里为这个隐藏在游戏中的组件、
I'm going to untick it. So now we should be able to see the capsule when we click play
我将取消它。所以现在我们应该能够看到胶囊，当我们点击播放时
and judging by its half height, we can know if what we've done is actually working. So
从它的一半高度来看，我们可以知道我们所做的事情是否真的有效。所以
I'm going to click compile in here, then click play. Now you can see this is the original
我将在这里点击编译，然后点击播放。现在你可以看到这是原来的
capsule height. Now I'm going to press F and this is the climbing capsule height. All right,
胶囊的高度。现在我按下F键，这就是爬升的胶囊高度。好了、
this is working and I'm sure you can notice that right now I cannot move this character
我相信你可以注意到，现在我不能再移动这个角色了。
anymore and that's because we'll need to handle the climb physics. Otherwise our input can
这是因为我们需要处理爬升的物理过程。否则我们的输入就不能
no longer move the character. So I'm going to press F again to exit the climb mode and
不能再移动这个角色了。所以我将再次按F键来退出爬升模式。
you can see this is the original capsule half height. Great. This is working. So this is
你可以看到这是原来胶囊的一半高度。很好。这是在工作。所以这就是
the roadmap that we'll follow later in the section. Feel free to refer back to the video
这就是我们在本节后面要遵循的路线图。如果你需要帮助，可以随时参考视频中的内容
if you need help. All right, it's time for you to do the same and I'll see you in the
如果你需要帮助。好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了，我们在下一节课上见。
next lecture.
下一讲见。
[Music]
[音乐]